RG 173:001, Company K Veteran Corps
Connecticut State Library
Company K Veteran Corps records
circa 1878-1948
Connecticut State Library
Company K Veteran Corps (Hartford, Conn.)
2.25 cubic feet
The Company K Veterans Corps of Hartford was founded in 1879 "to promote the interests and welfare of the active Company and preserve and continue the recollection of the service in the National Guard." All past members of Company K, First Regiment Infantry, Connecticut National Guard who had received an honorable discharge were eligible for election into this corps.
RG173_001
1989-029
Historical Note
The Company K Veterans Corps of Hartford was founded in 1879 "to promote the interests and welfare of the active Company and preserve and continue the recollection of the service in the National Guard." All past members of Company K, First Regiment Infantry, Connecticut National Guard who had received an honorable discharge were eligible for election into this corps.
Scope and Content
Contains organizational histories, minutes of meetings, newspaper clippings, speeches, programs, scrapbooks and photographs.
Arrangement
This collection is unprocessed. This is a preliminary container list.
Index Terms
Organizations:
Company K Veteran Corps (Hartford, Conn.)
Subjects:
Soldiers -- Connecticut; Veterans -- Connecticut
Document Types:
Clippings; Minutes; Scrapbooks; Photographs
Restrictions on Access
See the policy.
Provenance
Donated by Rev. Richard Y. Yerrington on July 19, 1989.
Container List
- Records, circa 1878-1948
  - Organizational histories and correspondence relating to previous donations to Connecticut State Library, circa 1948 (Box 1, Folder Envelope 1)
  - Orders to assemble for annual memorial service and roster of deceased members, 1914-1936 (Box 1, Folder Envelope 2)
  - Minutes, 1936-1940 (Box 1, Folder Folder 3)
  - Poem, "Co. K 'Scrap'" written by Corpl (sic) Solon P. Davis, 1884 (Box 1, Folder Folder 4)
  - Program for a production of Bronson Howard's comedy/drama "Shenandoah," performed by Co. K, First Regiment, Connecticut National Guard, 1898 (Box 1, Folder Item 5)
  - Newspaper clippings (Box 1, Folder Folder 6)
  - Addresses (speeches), 1890-1929 (Box 1, Folder Folder 7)
  - Souvenirs - Programs for annual meetings, 1893-1929 (Box 1, Folder Folder 8)
  - Bylaws and rosters, 1878-1888 (Box 1, Folder Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1882 (Box 1, Folder Folder 10)
  - History of Co. K Veterans Corps, 1901 (Box 1, Folder Item 11)
  - Memorial Committee, Co. K Veterans Association, 1931 (Box 1, Folder Item 12)
  - U.S. Army recruiting book, 1926 (Box 1, Folder Item 13)
  - Memorial Committee scrapbook, 1925-1932 (Box 1, Folder Item 14)
  - Record book, Co. K, 1886-1935 (Box 1, Folder Item 15)
  - Scrapbooks compiled by William A. Williard, historian, 1916-1929 (Box 1, Folder Folder 16)
  - Scrapbook, 1929-1935 (Box 1, Folder Item 17)
  - Scrapbook for the dedication of Soldiers Field, Northwood Cemetery, circa 1932 (Box 1, Folder Item 18)
  - Record book, Co. B (Box 1, Folder Item 19)
  - Photographs (Box 2)
    Various photographs both identified and unidentified of participants at the Corps annual meetings.
  - Parade and review at Camp Roberts, Niantic, Conn., 1905; oversize (Box 2, Folder Item 3)
  - Co. K at Camp Roberts, Niantic, Conn., 1905; oversize (Box 2, Folder Item 4)